tambay.ph 2015-12-25

# Privacy Policy : Vocabulary.com

  * Terms of Use
  * Privacy Policy

This privacy policy explains how Thinkmap, Inc. ("Thinkmap", "We", or "Us") collects and uses personal information that you ("you" or "your") provide on Vocabulary.com and on the Vocabulary.com App (collectively "Vocabulary.com"). This privacy policy was last updated on 2/6/2014.

## Collecting of Personal Information

In order to take advantage of certain features of Vocabulary.com, you must register. When you register for Vocabulary.com, we require that you provide your name, email address, and your date of birth. We also may collect information about the school you attend as well as other information that might appear on your user profile.

### User Profiles

Users have a public profile page that is linked from their name when it appears on Vocabulary.com. These pages present information that you provide such as a nickname or favorite word. The profile page may show information about your use of Vocabulary.com such as achievements earned, lists created, or your level.

### User Content

Users of Vocabulary.com can create various types of content ("User Content") that may be displayed publicly on Vocabulary.com. User Content includes information such as vocabulary lists, comments, and other types of material that is shared with the community.

### Children

Children under 13 are provided a limited feature set. All children who sign up must provide a parent's email address. The parent is then notified that the child has signed up to use Vocabulary.com. We ask that children chose a username that is not their real name. Children are restricted from certain parts of Vocabulary.com. For example, children do not have public profiles, and they cannot comment on articles or word lists. In addition, we do not collect children's email addresses, so all email communication from Vocabulary.com will be sent to the parent's email address.

If you are a parent, and you agree to let your child use Vocabulary.com, you agree and acknowledge that you permit your child to use Vocabulary.com and all features made available on Vocabulary.com as fully contemplated by us. As a parent, you understand that any personally identifiable information that your child provides in connection with registration or otherwise may be used by us as provided in this Privacy Policy. Except where the context indicates otherwise, the remainder of this Privacy Policy (including any discussion of the personally identifiable information that we may collect, use or disclose) shall apply equally to a child account and an account for someone over 13.

### User-Generated Content and Public Activities

We offer opportunities for you to engage in public activities on Vocabulary.com, including submitting comments and creating word lists. Any information you disclose in your public activities, along with your nickname or username and any image or photo, becomes public and may be used by us. Your public activities may also be read and collected by other users of the public activity areas on Vocabulary.com. We are not responsible for the personally identifiable information you choose to submit in these forums.

### Orders

If you purchase a product or service from us, we request certain personally identifiable information from you on our order form. You must provide contact information (such as name and email) and financial information (such as billing address, credit card number, expiration date). We use this information for billing purposes.  If we have trouble processing an order, we may use this information to contact you.

## Communication from Vocabulary.com

### Customer Service

Based upon the personally identifiable information you provide us, we will send you a welcoming email to verify your email address and password.  We will also communicate with you in response to your inquiries, to provide the services you request, and to manage your account. We will communicate with you by email only.

### Service-related Announcements

We will send you strictly service-related announcements on rare occasions when it is necessary to do so.  For instance, if our service is temporarily suspended for maintenance, we might send you an email.

Generally, you may not opt-out of these communications, which are not promotional in nature.

### Question Emails

If you have registered for Vocabulary.com, we may send you a periodic email that includes a personalized vocabulary question, and information about new content on Vocabulary.com. You may opt out of these emails. (Please see "Choice and Opt-out")

### Other Emails

You may opt in to receive other emails, such as comment notifications or emails when new material comes out on the blog. You may opt out of these emails. (Please see "Choice and Opt-out")

### Special Offers and Updates

We will occasionally send you information on products, services, special deals, and promotions. You may opt out of these emails.  (Please see "Choice and Opt-out")

## How We Handle Personally Identifiable Information

We may disclose personally identifiable information to provide products or services you've requested when we have your permission, and we may access, preserve and disclose account information and User Content if required to do so by law or in a good faith belief that such access preservation or disclosure is reasonably necessary to: (i) comply with legal process; (ii) enforce our [Terms of Use](http://www.vocabulary.com/terms/); (iii) respond to claims that any User Content violates the rights of third parties; (iv) provide support relating to Vocabulary.com; or (v) protect the rights, property or personal safety of the company, its users and the public.

We also may disclose personally identifiable information to an educator if you join a class owned by that educator. In this case, we may provide your name and your performance on particular activities on Vocabulary.com, so that the educator can better help you with your vocabulary learning.

If you are an educator and you add a student who is under 13 to your class, you acknowledge and agree that you are solely responsible for compliance with the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act of 1998, including, but not limited to, obtaining parental consent concerning collection of students' personal information used in connection with the provisioning and use of Vocabulary.com.

In addition, we transfer information about you if we are acquired by or merged with another company. In this event, we will notify you of any such change in ownership or control of your information.

## Aggregated Statistics

To improve Vocabulary.com, we track usage by aggregating information on what pages consumers access or visit.

### Cookies

Cookies are required to use Vocabulary.com. A cookie is a small amount of data, which often includes an anonymous unique identifier, that is sent to your browser from a website's server and stored on your computer's hard drive. We use cookies to record current session information, and to track the effectiveness of Vocabulary.com changes, marketing, and advertisements. We, and third-party vendors, including Google, may use first-party cookies and third-party cookies together to inform, optimize and serve ads based on someone’s past visits to Vocabulary.com.

## Third Parties

We contract with other companies to provide services on our behalf, including credit-card and billing processing, e-mail distribution, and analytics. Analytics may include 3rd party audience data (such as age, gender, and interests) on both our website and any mobile applications.

### Usage of collected information from tracking

We use collected information for the following general purposes: products and services provision, identification and authentication, services improvement, and research. We may use aggregated information (such as age, gender, and interests) to more effectively market Vocabulary.com to advertisers. We may use remarketing to advertise online. In this case, third-party vendors, including Google, may show our ads on sites across the Internet.

### Registration via Third-Party Tools

You can sign up for an account on Vocabulary.com by using third-party login credentials, such as your Facebook account information. This single sign-on service allows you to associate your existing third-party profile with an account on Vocabulary.com. As part of this process, we may access certain information contained in your third-party profile, such as your name, your profile picture, and your email address.

When you share or like (with or without adding your own comments) any Vocabulary.com articles or content to your Facebook profile, that action is governed by the [Facebook Privacy Policy](https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/). We do not track or store a record of those comments or actions.

## Choice and Opt Out

We provide you the opportunity to ‘opt-out’ of having your personally identifiable information used for certain purposes, when we ask for this information.  For example, if you purchase a product/service but do not wish to receive any additional marketing material from us, you can indicate your preference on our order form.

If you no longer wish to receive certain communications from us, you may opt-out of receiving them by either changing the email preferences section of the [My Account](https://www.vocabulary.com/account/) section, or through clicking on the provided link on any communication that we send.

If you would like to opt out or change the behavior of display advertising based on information collected by Google Analytics, follow this [link](https://www.google.com/settings/ads) to customize Google Display Network ads.

If you would like to opt out of Google Analytics, follow this [link](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/).

## Changes in this Privacy Statement

If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes to this privacy statement so that you are aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it.

We reserve the right to modify this privacy statement at any time, so please review it frequently.

## Contact Us

If you have any questions or suggestions regarding our privacy policy, please contact us through this [form](http://www.vocabulary.com/help/contactus).
